A Finding Aid to the Ben Benn Papers, 1905-1993, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Diaries, Notebooks, and Scrapbooks, 1915-1977, undated; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 11 Folders Boxes 4-5
  This series houses Velida Benn's diaries, notebook and notes, and Benn and Velida's scrapbooks. The diaries include references to Benn's activities, exhibitions and other projects, and the Benn family. Of interest are entries relating to Hilton Kramer, Seymour Hacker, and Hudson Walker, among others. The notebook and notes contain miscellaneous lists by Velida Benn. Three scrapbooks contain copies of correspondence, clippings, price lists, announcements, and parts of exhibition catalogs documenting Benn's museum and gallery shows from 1915 -1972. The arrangement of the scrapbooks has been retained in their original order.
  - Diaries, 1943-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18-20)
  - Diaries, 1960-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
  - Notebook and Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook #1, 1915-1960, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook #2, 1949-1967, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook #3, 1916-1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Personal Business Records, circa 1910-1979, undated; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 9 Folders Box 5
  Scattered personal business records that include miscellaneous receipts, a check register, a bank statement, an eviction notice, a file pertaining to the conservatorship of Ben Benn's estate, address books and lists, and lists and records of paintings purchased or held on consignment.
  - Paintings Sold or Held by Galleries, circa 1910- circa 1971, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Receipts, 1919-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Eviction Notice, Benn's residence at 206 West 105th Street, NY, NY, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Check Register, 1973-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Bank Statement, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Address Books and Lists, 1965-1966, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14-16)
  - Legal Proceeding Pertaining to Conservatorship of Ben Benn, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Artwork, 1924-1974, undated; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 6 Folders Box 5, 7; 6 oversized items
  Sketches and sketchbooks by Ben Benn, mostly in pencil, and fashion sketches, in pencil, by Velida Benn. Also found is an etching inscribed to Ben Benn from Marie G. Williams, 1924.
  - Etching, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Sketches, 1937-1974, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19-24)
  - Oversized Sketchbooks, 1957-1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Oversized Sketches, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Printed Material, 1911-1991, undated; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  This series houses announcements, exhibition catalogs, newspaper and magazine clippings, news bulletins, programs, reproductions and miscellaneous printed materials. Exhibition catalogs include Ben Benn: Painter, The Jewish Museum, 1965 and Ben Benn, An American Painter, 1884-1983, Hammer Galleries, 1983. Magazine clippings include numerous reviews of Benn's work by Sidney Geist, Hilton Kramer, and Sidney Tillim. Also found are miscellaneous literary and art-related periodicals featuring Benn's artwork and Artists and Writers Chap Books (1933-1935) that include artwork by Velida and Ben Benn.
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1911-1977, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25-34)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1918-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35-37)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1950-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1915-1982, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4-9)
  - Magazine clippings, 1916-1965, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10-14)
  - Artists and Writers Chapbook, 1933-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - News Bulletins, 1936-1937, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Programs, 1919-1950, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - Offprints, various, 1927-1940, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, 1914-1975, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20-24)
  - Reproductions, 1905-1975, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
  - Books, circa 1919, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28-30)
- Photographs and Negatives, 1920-1969, undated; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 6 Folders Box 6
  Photographs of works of art, personal photographs, and negatives that include images of Benn's paintings and exhibition installation shots; photographs and snapshots of Ben and Velida Benn, including an image of Benn taken by Peter A. Juley and Son; and negatives of Ben Benn and works of art.
  - Photographs of Works of Art, 1920-1964, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31-32)
  - Photographs of Ben and Velida Benn, 1936, 1963-1969, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Photographs of Exhibition Installations, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Photographs of Family Members, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Negatives, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 36)